In this video, I'll be teaching you how
to do one of the most unique
combinations of a GPT and an external
database that works with the GPT.
Meaning, you're giving a custom version
of chat GPT custom memories. The use
case we'll be doing that with in this
video is a journaling GPT where every
time you interact with it, it looks into
the database, brings in any journal
entries from the past seven days to come
up with custom questions to ask you
today. Then you type out the answers and
it stores them back in the database. And
the way we're doing this is with an
automation. So what practically happens
is we have a make automation in the
middle. And when you engage the GPT, a
make automation gets the data into your
GPT. So you get a custom start. And once
you're done journaling, you send your
journal entry to the automation which
stores it in the database. Now to be
clear, this is not a beginner level
automation, but I believe this is well
worth teaching because you can customize
it to do other things than journals.
Essentially, I'm showing you how to
build a custom chatbot inside of chat
GPT with an external storage attached to
it. And at this point, I also want to
point out that this video is sponsored
by Make. They approached us to do a
video with their product. And we were
very excited to actually do that because
we did not build this automation for the
collaboration. We built it cuz we
thought it was really unique and we were
going to teach it in our community
before they even approached us because
we like teaching automations in make as
we find that it's the perfect balance
for beginners. Now again, not a beginner
automation, but don't worry, I have my
trusty iPad here. I'll do my very best
to explain the theory, and then we're
going to do a step by step, which is
also going to include me giving you
everything to copy paste, including the
make blueprint. But because we're
working with JSON objects and notion
databases and everything here, you can
start by importing my blueprint, which
you can also find in the description
below, but then you'll have to reconnect
everything, but it might be a good
starting point to leave less room for
errors. So, with that being said, let's
have a closer look at what we're about
to build here. Okay, so let's begin by
talking about what you need to actually
accomplish this. As I mentioned, this is
no beginner automation, but the tools
involved are quite simple and very
similar to many of the tutorials we
already did on this channel. First of
all, we'll be using a GPT inside of Chat
GPT running on their newest model, GPT5.
Those are only accessible on the premium
plan, which starts at $20 a month. Then
you will need a make account, and a free
account will totally suffice for this.
If you like the automation, want to keep
using it, you can upgrade to build out
more on your account. But for the sake
of this tutorial, you only need to sign
up for the free account. And then
lastly, to store our data here, we'll be
using notion as it's a free software
that allows to get going here without
paying for something like Air Table. And
in my experience, if you're automating,
it does work better than something like
Google Sheets. In terms of setup of all
these free, it's quite simple. Chat GBD,
let's be real, if you're watching this
channel, you probably have an account
already. With Make, you can use the
first link in the description to get
started for free, which in my
experience, it's usually the easiest to
just loging in with your Google account.
And with Notion, it's the same deal. You
can just sign up for free, but in the
video, we'll be setting up a connection.
So, what I want you to do now in
preparation is copy over this journal
GPT template that we prepared for you
into your own Notion account. You simply
go to the link in the description. It is
completely free. It's just a database
template. and you simply go on here and
click duplicate which will allow you to
add it to your workspace like so. By
clicking this I have added this to my
private workspace and those are all our
prerequisites. So with that being said
we're ready to look at how to build this
automation. But I want to do one thing
before we do that and that's because
we're exploring some new and more
advanced concepts than what we've done
previously on this channel. And for that
I want to take some time to actually
talk about them. So look, if you're
already familiar with what web hooks are
and how they function and what JSONs
are, feel free to skip this section. We
put timestamps down below so you can get
to the practical implementation part.
But in case you could use a refresher,
which for my experience, most people
working with these things, unless you're
a seasoned programmer, a refresher like
this can be really useful or you're not
familiar at all. Well, let me clear my
iPad here and explain these two
absolutely essential concepts in
automation and development that if
you're going to be building automations
like this, you just need to know. and I
promise I'll keep it as concise as I
can. Okay, so first up, web hooks. What
is a web hook? Well, you can essentially
think of the concept of a web hook as a
tool that enables communication between
two applications. So, I'm going to
employ my advanced drawing skills here.
If so, if we have app number one over
here and app number two over here,
right, that's actually not so bad. If
app number one fires a web hook, okay,
that's my illustration of a signal.
Well, that web hook is going to have a
unique ID. It's very similar to API key,
which it's going to be looking for. So
let's say in this case the web hook is
named peanut one. I don't know why
peanut one. I just came up with that. So
if app one is firing and saying hey I'm
firing a web hook with the name peanut
one and app number two is actively
looking for peanut one and then it hits
the exact web hook and it sees that web
hook says peanut one then it allows for
these two to connect and exchange data.
I think that's a pretty good way of
explaining it actually. So practically
the web hook is not going to be called
peanut one but it's going to be
something like cg7y i ks3 etc. And the
make is going to be scanning for this
exact web hook and we're going to set up
our GPT to be sending that exact web
hook whenever the user decides that he
finished his journal entry for the day.
So in our illustration this is make this
the journaling GPT and we will be
sending this package over. I'll make it
look like a document. Let's see how I
do. And this document is going to be a
JSON. And if you're not familiar with
JSONs, that's completely fine. You can
just think of it as PDFs are made for
humans and JSONs are made for computers.
It's just a different format that makes
it really easily readable for programs.
So nothing gets lost as we send it
through the web hook. And this JSON will
have a very specific format. For this, I
will open a new page and we'll be
setting this exact format that we'll be
sending over up in the very first step
in our automation. And what the
so-called data structure within the JSON
will contain is the following items. an
action, a note, and then just so you
know, within the note, we'll have sub
items. This is the stuff we're going to
store in our database, which is going to
make this journal real nice and
convenient. We'll be storing another
date, a title, the actual content of
your journal entry, the mood of the day,
tags, and one more called note ID, and
then two dates, from date and to date.
So to sum up, we're going to be sending
this JSON with all the details of your
journal entry, including the mood,
dates, the actual journal entry, and
more via web hook to our automation,
which will make sure everything is
safely placed within our database. So
that's the theory. Now, let's get into
the step by step of actually setting
this up. Okay, so our setup is going to
begin inside of chat GPT. We're going to
be setting up this GPT. Then we'll move
into make to get the database and all
the connections, right? And finally,
we'll finish the GPT. So, what I need
you to do is inside of the chatb
account, go over to GPTs. On the top
right, say create and then you can pull
up this page from the description of
this video called journal GPT setup. And
we just prefilled some of the fields
here that you'll be copying over. So,
for the name, you can call this journal
GPT. Here's a quick description of what
it does. For the instructions, we
carefully crafted this over many
iterations. Feel free to customize it,
but this is what we came up with. Simply
copy paste this into the instructions
here. And as we're right here, I need
you to customize one thing right now.
This is important, otherwise it won't
work. Here under time zone, just replace
this user time zone. So in my case, I'm
going to say Lisbon/ Europe. We can just
do this format of city/continent
and it's going to work every time. And
then for conversation starter, a simple
let's begin will do. We have no
knowledge files and as a recommended
model from our testing already we found
that GPT5 actually works best here and
that is for the reason of its
instruction following being the best
amongst all open AAI models meaning that
these detailed instructions they include
a lot of nuance and details and GP5
simply follows these the best and that's
why it's the best choice here. We want
this to work reliably for capabilities.
We'll turn everything on including the
code interpreter and data analysis. And
then that concludes our initial setup.
after we're done with the make part. We
will come back here to create the new
action. But to do this, we need the web
hook details that we'll be creating
within the make automation. And that's
why we're going to leave this right
here. Maybe one more thing. I'm just
going to generate the image with deli.
And with that being said, we're ready to
move on into the make part, which will
be a bit more technical, but this
tutorial will document every click, so
you have a chance of recreating this
from scratch yourself. Okay. Okay, now
inside of make we will start with a web
hook as that is what will be triggering
our automation here which is essentially
going to be the middle part between the
GPT and our database and our journey
starts within our account under
scenarios here I will create a brand new
scenario and then as we explained what
we're actually going to be doing here in
the illustrations with the iPad in the
last segment we can move through this a
bit quicker first we'll be adding the
web hook and here you want a custom web
hook so we can create a brand new one by
clicking add and And I'm going to say my
journal tutorial web hook. I'm going to
add an API key here just to make this
thing secure. I'm going to also add
that. Change the name to my tutorial API
key. And here you can really make this
as simple or as complicated as you want
to. For this tutorial, I will simply say
tutorial 1 2 3 4 5. Create this. And now
that's a password to my web hook. Let's
make sure that not everybody on the
internet can just start using this. When
I click show advanced settings, it will
allow me to add a data structure here.
And as I mentioned, we're going to be
sending a very specific type of data
structure across here because we don't
just want to capture the message. We
want to capture a whole bunch of
information from our journal to actually
store that in our database. Again, if
any of this confuses you, make sure to
check out the explanation section where
you also got to enjoy my drawing skills.
So, for data structure, we'll also be
adding a brand new data structure. And
I'll just say my tutorial data
structure. And here I will be adding a
specification. And this is where we'll
be adding all the objects we discussed.
This is the type of thing that you don't
really need to understand in depth right
now. You can kind of just follow along
this tutorial and do exactly what I do.
And then by using this, you will kind of
understand how it goes from GPT to
database through what we do right here.
But what I'm going to do is I'm going to
set up the fields we discussed earlier.
So the first one is an action. The type
is text here. And I want to make this
one required actually, which means it's
always expecting it. What I like to do
is I always like to close these down
after I finish them. It just maintains
my overview. I'm going to add another
one. The next one is note type is
collection. This one is also required.
And then within the note I'm actually
going to have multiple sub items. So in
this specification I'm going to say add
item. Just say date. This type I'm
changing to date also required. Collapse
this. We want the title which is text
also required. Then we want content
which is text also required. mood, which
is a text, and this one is actually not
required, meaning it's optional. Tags,
and just make sure to switch tags to an
array right here. This will allow us to
create a tagging system within our
notion database, which is kind of a neat
feature because then you're going to be
able to return to some of your journal
entries later down the line really
easily. Not required. Okay, so we added
tags and then we're also going to add
one called node ID. Keep it as text.
It's not required. And we can move on to
the next one. And actually I want to
change one thing which is the note is
actually not required here. It only
needs the action to work. I mean this is
not going to make a practical difference
but just bear with me as we set this up
step by step and then you can use it and
tweak it to your liking. So I can close
out the note and then we need two last
fields to round this out. One of is
going to be from underscore date. I'm
going to change the type to date and
then to underscore date. The type is
also date and also not required. Okay.
So we're done here. I'm going to save
this data structure. And I know that
might have been a lot, but honestly, you
don't need a deep understanding of this.
Just follow along and it's going to make
this app work. And then you can do your
thing later on. So, as you can see, this
is already looking for the web hook
right here. Right now, we're not sending
any. So, we can just move on to the next
step, which in our case is going to be
our router. So, under flow control,
there's these routers, which allow you
to set up different scenarios in the
automation. In total, we want four of
these. So, I'm just going to click plus
twice, but a lot of it is going to be
identical. So let's just starting out by
building one which is our notion step
and we will set up this notion step in
just a second here. But before we do
that we have to define when this
automation should go down this
particular path as we'll have four of
these in the end. Where you do that is
you click this wrench right here. You
say set up a filter and right here you
can pick when it will go down this first
path. So I want it to go down this first
path when the action from the web hook
equals to create note. This is what we
set up inside of the GBT to send through
the web hook. So whenever it wants to
create a new note, it will send exactly
this create note. You can review that
within the GPT prompt. And then I can
also label it. And now this very first
path will happen if we want to create a
new note. Okay, now we're ready to start
building out this path with the notion
step. Now to do that, if you've never
worked with notion make before, we have
to do a setup one time. This takes a few
steps. So if you have a connection like
me here, you could pick that. But I'm
going to go through this with you step
by step just to make sure that everybody
can do this while following the
tutorial. So you're going to say add and
then here you're going to say notion
internal. I'm just going to call this
the notion internal tutorial connection.
And then it wants this internal
integration token right here. And the
way to get that is if I go over to my
notion and I'm on my database here, the
journal GPT that we copied over in the
beginning. You can click the three dots,
go here into connections and say manage
connections. And then all the way at the
bottom you want to go to develop or
manage integrations. This will open up a
new browser tab in which you can just
click new integration. You name it. So
we're going to say journal GPT tutorial
connection to make this super clear.
This is the notion workspace I'm in.
It's an internal connection. And that is
it. I just say save right here. And when
I click configure integration settings,
this is set up. And we see our internal
integration secret right here. I'm just
going to show it and copy it over here
and paste it. Right now, when I save
this, there's one last step we need to
do to actually make this work. And this
couldn't be any simpler. Back inside of
the notion database, you click the three
dots again. And now, if you go under
connections, if I look for tutorial,
you're going to see the journal GPT
tutorial connection. If I select this
and confirm, we're all done. Our
database is hooked up to the automation,
which will allow us to put anything we
want inside of the database from here on
out. And if you ever use make again, you
don't have to go through this process
again. and it's set up and you can just
pick your connection from this list and
it's right there. So that's the
connection. Now we just have to tell
make which database we want to edit
things in. Select from the list is fine.
And for database ID, it's actually
really simple. You just have to look for
the name. So journal GPT, we don't have
to spell out the full thing and click
okay and it should find it
automatically. That's it right there.
Okay. Okay, so you can already see some
of the tags that are in the database pop
up here, but we won't actually be
needing those because now it's time to
hook up the data we got from the GPT and
put it in the right place in the
database. So, we're going to start up
top here with the title inside of the
note. That's this title right here. For
tags, we actually want to map. So, you
flip this little switch and then you
select tags. For content, we pick
content. For mood, we want to flip map
again and we pick the mood. And for the
start time, we have to do a little trick
here. And I have to admit while we built
this automation we actually use chat GBT
to exactly give us the right thing to
write here. But essentially you have to
look for parse date which will allow you
to reformat the date into a format that
notion will accept seamlessly. These are
intermediate to advanced operations
which you can do with all of your data
to essentially transform it from one
format into another. In this case we're
going to be transforming it from the
format that GPD gives us into a format
that notion wants. So we're going to be
parsing this data. We're going to be
filling in two things in the brackets
here. So, first up, right here, we want
the dates that we passed from the notes
here. And then in the second part, you
can just put in X, and this will work.
Just trust me on this. Then, in the end,
we say include time. Yes. And voila,
that is the notion step. Now, I know
this is becoming a lot of step-by-step
following, but hey, that's how it is
when you get into things that go beyond
the basics. Just super quick anecdote,
and we'll get back to it. I remember
back in the day when I was learning
Photoshop and I went through some of
these tutorials where for 5 minutes
straight it was just well you set this
slider to 74 and this slider to 14.5 and
then the gsh and blur settings should be
these five exact settings and you kind
of just followed it hit enter but then
the damn thing worked and it felt like
magic and it gave you that motivation to
actually go ahead and learn about these
steps and I hope this tutorial does the
same. So if you feel a bit confused,
don't worry. It's completely normal when
you're pushing beyond the boundaries of
your knowledge. And hopefully I'm doing
good enough of a job of explaining this
so you can follow along well and then
the whole thing works and then you can
learn exactly about parsing dates later
on if you feel like it. So for the next
step, we need to create a JSON object
right here, which we can do by clicking
plus JSON and then create JSON. We'll be
doing this with the Eigore diary node
data structure. So it's important to
select that. And here we're going to be
pre-selecting the corresponding fields.
And most of them are going to come from
these properties values down here. So
for the date, we want properties,
values, and then date. And then I want
you to select the start. And then on the
title, we want to open it up and use the
plain text title. That's just the title
without any formatting. That's what we
want here. For content, we again want to
go into content, plain text. Beautiful.
For mood, we take the name of the mood.
And for tags, we'll be adding an item.
And then in here you actually want to
use the map function to make this work
properly. And in the first part of this
mapping function you want the whole list
of tags. This is a programming specific
thing but if you have these two brackets
in the end you know it's a list so it
can contain multiple tags. And then the
second half we want the name of the tag.
So just select the name right here. And
then finally for the note ID we want to
go all the way to the top and use the
database item ID. And this will allow us
to identify which item in the database
it exactly is as we pass this JSON
around. Okay. So that rounds out this
step. You don't have to understand all
of that. All I need you to know is that
this is sort of the package that helps
us communicate between the GPT and the
database. Okay. And as we have the
complete JSON that contains all the data
we need, we can add one final step here,
which is a web hook. And you're just
going to paste in this custom code here
where the response type is single note.
And then the single note is the JSON
that we created in this string. So I'm
going to go in here and just link that
like so. Say save. And that is really
the first branch complete. So to recap,
if ever the GPT is going to be sending
out a web hook via its actions, this
automation will catch it, decide what
type of web hook that was, and if that
web hook is saying we should create a
note, then it will go into our database,
create a new database item, reformat the
data it got into a beautiful JSON, and
then fire another web hook, which the
GPT can then again catch to continue
working. Now, we need a few different
routes because not in every case are we
creating a brand new node, right? As I
told you, we also want the GPT to be
able to pick up the last nodes from the
database. So, it's not just writing but
also reading. And for that, we have some
other routes here. So, in the second
route, what we want to happen is the
action to exactly match update note
because the GPT also has the ability to
change the database entries. I'll also
name it that so it's nicely visible on
here. And then we want another notion
action this time because this is about
updating. We're going to be updating the
database item. All we need is a quick
search. And if I look for journal and if
I just type in the first letters of the
database name again we link it up here
for the ID we're going to be using the
note ID right here. For the title we got
the title tags we're mapping and giving
it the tags. Content is content. Mood
again we're mapping giving it the mood.
And for the date we'll have to do the
same little trick as before where we're
parsing the date to make it the right
format. First part is date. Second part
is yet again x just like before. And
then finally we need to set include time
to yes for this to work reliably. Say
save. Then we need to create another
JSON. So JSON create JSON. And then here
I can already choose the data structure
which is going to be Eigor's diary node.
And here we'll be using data from the
latest step the notion action that
updates. So for the date we want to use
the date start. For the title the title
in plain text. For the content the
content in plain text. For the mood we
want the name of the mood. And we'll be
mapping the tags. And you need to use
this mapping function here for this to
work. And all the way at the bottom on
the properties value as with the others,
you just give it the tags which is an
array. And that essentially means it's a
list of all the tags. And here you just
type name. And for note ID, finally we
give it the database item ID. Click save
and the JSON is set up. And then we
round this out with another web hook.
Insert the web hook. We can keep the
single note because that's what we're
sending here. Again, it's just a single
piece of data. But then the note
changed. So as you see, I copy pasted
that over from the first web hook and it
was still linking to this JSON which was
indicated by the number four. You have
to be careful with little details like
this single node is the new JSON which
you can see here by the number 10. So
I'm just going to click that save. And
now it sends the web hook with this
JSON. Okay, two more paths and we got
this. So next path is yet again going to
be determined by action but this time we
want to get the notes. Also adding that
as a label. If you've been following
closely this will hopefully make sense.
Get nodes is to retrieve the nodes when
the GPT gets engaged. This first one was
for writing a new database item. The
second one is for updating an existing
database item and this one is just to
fetch one of the previous database
items. So the notion action therefore is
going to be search objects because we
need to find one of the database items.
Again, we can just link up the database
by looking for the name of it journal.
Say okay, beautiful. There it is. And
then we can up this limit to 100 in case
you're going to be using this a lot and
you want to look over a total of up to
100 entries. But on this one, we
actually have to use the filter because
we don't want to look at every single
database item. As I said, this GPT is
set up to only look at the journal
entries from the past week. So here, you
could change that, but to only look at
the past week, we need to set up a
filter. And we're going to be filtering
for the date. So I'll set up the filter
for the date. And then if I do that,
there's this option in here that says
date on or after. Okay. And when we
select this date as before, we again
need to parse this date to get it into
the format that works with notion here.
So in the first part, we're going to do
the from date and the second part just
the X as before. Again, this just
changes the formatting so that notion
can actually read it. And we add a and
rule here. And now we want to go to
date, but this time we want date on or
before. This allows us to create a
little date range for all the nodes
between two dates. Just like before, we
need to parse the date so notion can
read it. And here we'll be taking the
two date and the X here. And this will
filter for all the nodes between this
date and this date. Save that filter
just like that. Okay. Then we need
another JSON. So I'm just going to pick
this notion step. Take the ego diary
note. And then from the notion step,
we're putting the data into here. Just
like with the previous two paths, date
start. I want the title in plain text. I
want the content in plain text. I want
the mood name. And for the tags, we want
to use the map function here like so.
And then here we want the tags and the
name. And then for note ID, we want to
use the page ID. Amazing. We're really
getting close to actually making this
work. While we tested this, there is one
error that could occur here, which is if
there's nothing in your database, this
step will throw an error. So, the way we
can handle that in here is by
right-clicking this JSON saying add
error handler resume. And then here, you
just want to enter square brackets,
which means this is an empty list. So,
in this case, we'll keep everything
working as it will return an empty list
in case there's nothing in the database,
which can happen. Okay. And then we
round out this one with another webbook
response. I'm just going to copy this
over from the other one. But here we
actually got to change three things.
This and this right here because it's
not a single note anymore. We filtered
for multiple nodes. So say notes right
here, notes right here. And then here
you want to pick the correct JSON, the
JSON from step 14. And save this out cuz
we want to send this one for the web
hook. Because when we looked inside of
the notion database and searched for
date range, if it's multiple days, it
can return more than one note. So it's
not the same thing as a single note
before. Okay, let's finish the last
path, which will round out the
automation. This one is going to be all
about getting the tags, which honestly
with the journaling example here is kind
of a nice to have, but if you rebuild
this automation to do other things,
having things tagged can be extremely
useful. Sometimes even mission critical.
So, this is how you do it. You set up
this route to be to get the tags. We'll
add a notion step. This time, we want to
get a database, the same database as
before. Click save. And then we want one
last web hook which is going to be a web
hook response. And then this one we need
to customize a little bit. So the
response type is tags. And then all the
tags we want to pass on as a list which
we do by giving these square brackets
which creates a list. Then inside the
square brackets we want the map function
like so. And then right here in the
first part of the map function I want
the tags but I want the list here under
options. All the options we have. And
then in the second part we just say
name. Click save. And that is it right
there. That is the full step by step on
how to build this automation that can
now be customized for so many different
use cases. But we're going to finish out
our journaling GPT here by heading back
over into chat GPT. And now hooking this
automation up with the GPT. So
previously we finished all the other
fields here except of the action. And
the action is what's going to be
communicating with the automation here.
So let's create a new action. And then
what you want to do here is take the
notion page I gave to you. And then here
at the bottom you can see JSON. And you
can copy this by clicking copy. And this
entire JSON is what links this to the
automation. All the things we set up in
there is specified in this JSON. So you
can see there's different mood types. It
either sends single notes or notes. All
the things that we set up in the
automation is in here. So all I do is
copy and paste that JSON in here. And
then I just need to fill out one single
thing right here where it says web hook
URL. This is essential. This is where we
connect it. Remember what I explained to
you that we're going to be firing a web
hook with the GPT which the automation
is going to be listening for. Well, this
is the listening step right here. And
it's listening for this very specific
URL. So I'm going to copy this address
to the clipboard. Head back over to my
GPT and paste that in here. And make
sure nothing gets lost here. Right. In
this case, when I pasted it, it actually
deleted the second quotation mark. So, I
absolutely want to preserve that
otherwise it won't work. So, it's URL
and quotation marks colon space
quotation mark then the URL then the
quotation marks. If you do this, you
should see a check diary action pop up
here. And this is what's going to be
linking our GBT to the automation to the
database and backwards. Okay, there's
one more thing because to make this
extra secure, we did set up a API key.
So you need to go to authentication up
here and actually set it up to otherwise
it won't be able to speak to each other.
It's like a password for the
communication here. So off type I'm
going to set to custom. And remember
right here we set this up my tutorial
API key. And actually to be fair I
already forgot what I set this to. So
I'm just going to set a new one and
remove the first one. Going to call this
my second tutorial API key. The value is
going to be tutorial 1 2 3 4 5. Actually
thinking back that might have been what
I set for this tutorial. I will simply
say tutorial 1 2 3 4 5. Anyway, what I
want to do here is copy this right here.
Send the API key using the X make API
key. HTTP header. That is what it wants
down here, the custom header name. So,
I'm going to paste that in here. And
then the API key was tutorial 1 2 3 4 5.
Save. We're done. Would you believe
that? So, let's create the GPT. But I
actually want to only create this one
for myself. So, that concludes the GPT
setup. But I have to do one more thing
in the make automation and I have to
turn this on immediately as data arrives
and for that to work I actually need to
save the changes here. This had some
unsaved changes. Okay, we can fix that.
Run scenario immediately and now this is
running and listening. And now if we go
into a brand new conversation with the
GPT and say let's begin. It will fetch
our latest journal entries and all of
our tags. And you will see that it will
be engaging me with a custom message
that is based on what is in my database
where I talk about development and
pedal. And then it's talking to me as if
it knew because it does. And if I share
a new message, I can say save to
database. And I'll just pull over the
notion database here because you will
see it using the action up here. And
voila, it populates into the database.
And this way you can set up a two-way
connection straight from within chat GPT
to access an external database as your
very own storage. As mentioned before, I
also included a blueprint to this entire
scenario. So you can just go in here and
make say more import blueprint and then
bring the whole automation in, but you
will have to reconnect everything one by
one to your own accounts. But this way
you at least have a starting point where
less can go wrong. So if you want to try
this out for yourself, you can get one
month of make for free from the first
link in the video's description below.
And that's it for today. Something a bit
more in-depth, a bit more advanced. The
options are vast here. You could really
customize this to do many other things.
And that interface of being within chat
is something that over 80% of the users
will resonate with cuz it is the most
popular LLM platform in the world. And
now you know how to extend it with
external memory. All right, my name is
Igor and I hope you have a wonderful